linuxuprising.com 2019-12-18

# Privacy Policy - Linux Uprising Blog

This Privacy Policy covers Linux Uprising ("We" or "Us"), which includes the www.linuxuprising.com website and its social media pages. The Privacy Policy governs your access to and use of the services, websites, and applications offered through Linux Uprising (the “Services”). Please read this statement carefully before using or proceeding to access Linux Uprising. Your use of Linux Uprising indicates that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy and indicates your agreement to abide by the Terms of Use in effect and to be subject to this policy.

## 1\. Information Collection

Linux Uprising or third parties may collect information from our users at several different points.

**Comment Service, Email Subscription and Account Information** – In order to further enhance the user experience, Linux Uprising allows users to comment, enabling users to discuss and contribute to topics posted on www.linuxuprising.com.  
Users have the option of using an existing Disqus, Google, Facebook or Twitter account, or signing up for Disqus, and to do so must either submit some valid information or set up an anonymous account. Linux Uprising uses this information to screen out users who leave comments prohibited by our Terms of Use, to make notifications to users when necessary or to pick out topics of interest to commenters.  
You may link your account to certain third party services and to do so, may be required to provide your login information for those services. Since you login via a third party service, we will receive an identifying token from that service, which will allow us to access some information from your account on that service, so that we can, for example, send you a message through that service. Linux Uprising does not receive or store passwords from your third party service and will not pass information provided when you register via a third party service to any other organization.

For those who subscribe to receive emails when new articles are posted, Linux Uprising collects email addresses which can include personal data. Such data is used by a third party, Feedburner, to operate its email update service. Feedburner also provides an RSS feed of blog posts and related information on Linux Uprising for the purpose of providing that information to those who wish to access blog information via an RSS reader or similar program. [Here](https://feeds.feedburner.com/LinuxUprising) is a link to the Linux Uprising RSS feed.

Emails are collected for those who post comments or subscribe to new comment notifications.

Feedburner is operated by Google, while new comment notifications by Disqus.

Linux Uprising has no control over these tools, is not affiliated with Google, Feedburner, or Disqus beyond using its services as described and does not collect any data as a result of their use. Google and Disqus may collect and/or process your data in these circumstances. If you have any concerns regarding Google’s use of your personal data following use of these tools, you may read Google’s policy [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy/update) and [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy), and Disqus' [here](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy).

In addition to this, some blog posts or comments may include personal data such as the names of people who wrote blogposts, posted information elsewhere online, made comments or similar. These posts are often shared on social media including Linux Uprising's Twitter, Google+ and Facebook pages. The privacy policies of Twitter, Google+ and Facebook will apply to information posted on their websites.

Linux Uprising respects your personal data and takes care to maintain its confidentiality.

If you would like any personal data which is included in blog posts or comments to be removed or have any questions about the Linux Uprising website data privacy policy, please email Linux Uprising at contact [at] linuxuprising [dot] com.

**Cookies** – Linux Uprising or third parties may use cookies, web beacons, HTML5 local storage, JavaScript, and other similar technologies to help us understand how you use the Services and help us provide the Services and advertising to you.  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to information about the user. We may use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once the user closes the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user’s hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following the user’s internet browser help file directions.  
We store a cookie on each user’s machine that contains user specific information. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. If you reject all cookies, you will not be able to use Services that require you to “sign in,” and you may not be able to take full advantage of all offerings. However, not all Services require that you accept cookies. Some of our business partners may use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies. You may read more about our cookies in general and the cookies used on this website by clicking this link: <https://www.linuxuprising.com/p/cookie-policy.html>

**Links** – Linux Uprising contains links to other sites, including affiliate marketing links encoded by third parties. Such third parties do not collect any personally identifiable information unless you visit the referenced site. Please be aware that Linux Uprising is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Linux Uprising.

**Surveys & Contests **– From time-to-time our site requests information via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you may choose whether or not to participate and therefore disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.

**Embedded Content** — You should also be aware that some content delivered through Linux Uprising originates with another content provider (embedded YouTube or Vimeo videos for example). Such other content providers may place “cookies” on your computer, or otherwise gather information about you, including by asking you to provide information through the content player itself. Again, it is up to you to review the terms of use and privacy policy of the originators of such content.

**Log Files** – Like most standard website servers we use log files to log certain information about how you use Linux Uprising. Since this website is hosted on Google's Blogger, this information is stored on third party servers, and may be used by third party service providers in order to provide site personalization and assess general user interest in various internal and third party products and services. We do not, however, collect IP addresses or log IP address information.

## 2\. Advertising

 **Ad Serving** – The ads appearing on these websites are delivered to you by a web advertising vendor and/or by Linux Uprising's own proprietary advertising delivery software. In order to serve ads to you, we may use information collected during your searches or visits to our websites and information that we specifically acquire from third parties.

**Advertising and Cookies** – Some of our third party advertising partners may distribute cookies to users in advertisements that are provided to us. Linux Uprising has no access to or control over these cookies once we have received the advertisements. Some of these advertisers and services we use to deliver advertising may be engaging in online behavioral advertising as defined by the Digital Advertising Alliance and FTC.  
Linux Uprising currently uses Google Adsense and Ezoic to serve ads. You may read about how Google uses information from sites or apps that use their services here: <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites> and Ezoic here: <https://www.linuxuprising.com/privacy.html>

**Affiliate Advertising** – We participate in affiliate advertising and allow affiliate links to be encoded on some of our pages. This means that we may earn a commission when you click on or make purchases via affiliate links and affiliate partners may use cookies to understand your use of the Services.  
Linux Uprising does not provide any Personally Identifiable Information to third-party advertising companies. 

**Opt-out** – We provide the following links to opt-out of cookies provided by both our first party ad server and many third party advertising partners who may be engaging in online behavioral advertising:  
First Party Opt-out – Please visit this link to opt-out of cookies from our first party ad serving vendor, Google: <https://www.google.com/privacy/ads/>; Third Party and Online Behavioral Advertising Opt-out – Please visit this link to opt-out of cookies from over 50+ major third party behavioral advertising providers: <https://www.aboutads.info/choices/>. You may also change the cookie settings for Linux Uprising by clicking here.

## 3\. Notification of Changes

Whenever Linux Uprising changes its privacy policy, we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy page, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. You are responsible for reviewing and becoming familiar with any changes to this agreement.

## 4\. Contact Information

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please email us: contact [at] linuxuprising [dot] com.

## 5\. Last Update

This Privacy Policy was updated on March 9, 2019: mentioned Disqus in the Privacy Policy, which is now used instead of Blogger's own comment system.
